## ANDREAS LILLEVANG BECH

1271 Stoner Ave., 90025 Los Angeles, California bech@usc.edu https://github.com/andreaslillevangbech +1 (213) 649 9943

### ABOUT ME

I am a 32-year-old from Denmark currently living in Los Angeles, pursuing a PhD at USC. I specialize in game theory, prediction and learning, data economics, and the study of equilibria and truth-telling in prediction contests. I enjoy reading books, soccer, and hiking around Los Angeles.

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Southern California, Los Angeles

September 2020 - present

PhD student in Economics

I study firm pricing and consumer welfare in monopoly markets, with a focus on how information endowments and the possibility of disclosure affect market outcomes, including separate information markets (consumer data, platform intermediaries). My research also examines dynamic pricing scenarios where firms lack prior knowledge of consumer preferences but can gather data over time.

#### Toulouse School of Economics, France

August 2018 - 2019 July

Master 2, Econometrics and Economic Theory (Doctoral Track)

This is the first year of the PhD program at TSE. The material is standard and equivalent to PhD programs in the US.

#### Toulouse School of Economics, France

August 2017 - June 2018

Master 1, Econometrics and Statistics, path of Decisions Mathematics

Small program at TSE focusing on mathematics linked to economics, combining methods from Game Theory, Computer Science and Statistics. This is my favorite year of education from where I draw most of my inspiration.

## University of Copenhagen, Denmark

July 2012 - June 2017

B.Sc in Economics.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Research Assistant at Copenhagen Business School

September 2019 - August 2020

· RA in Center for Financial Frictions (FRIC) with Professor Lasse Heje Pedersen, Professor Peter Feldhütter and Associate Professor Jens Dick-Nielsen.

### Master Thesis on Machine Learning and Forecasting

May 2019 - 2019 July

· How to use a large set of predictors effectively to forecast of asset prices using sparsity methods and statistical learning. Advisor: Professor Nour Meddahi.

### Master 1 Memoir on Mechanism Design

April 2018 - July 2018

· Novel mechanism to find treatment effects in RCT's with Moral Hazard. Extension of paper by Chassang, Padro i Miquel and Snowberg (2011). Advisor: Professor Takuro Yamashita.

#### **B.Sc Thesis on International Economics**

March 2017 - June 2017

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Concepts Linux, Machine Learning, Game Theory

**Programming languages** Python, Haskell, C++, R, Julia